SUMMARY

6+ years of outstanding record in developing digital strategy and driving business transformation across different verticals in Supply Chain Management and Operations. Have experience of building teams to improve overall supply chain efficiency. Have also implemented several projects and operations on multi-functional teams focusing on inventory management, procurement, logistics using SAP.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Senior Supply Chain Planner, Bulbrite, New Jersey, USA

July 2022-Oct 2022

- Maintained the accuracy of BOM, inventory and other product attributes as defined
- Lead monthly Sales and Operations Planning process from demand consensus building with sales and marketing with senior management.
- Analyzed and reviewed retail POS, shipment history and inventory trends and monitored sales achievements.
- Identified KPI behavior and implemented data, reported and lead continuous process improvement initiatives.
- Prepared and maintained comparative reports that support continuous analysis of shipments, consumption trends and promotional reconciliation to validate and reported forecast variances.
- Prepared and distributed the various demand planning reports that support the business operations.

Supply Chain Analyst, Samsung, New Jersey, USA

Sep 2019-July 2022

- Executed the operational duties of important consumers of Samsung, supported regional Samsung Home Appliances business expansion and improved sales by 12% up to \$5M.
- Managed and improved order fulfillment including but not limited to site/warehouse management, optimization, Sales delivery order creation, order status, cross shipping by 10%.
- Created dashboards for TV forecasts, sales by using Tableau by analyzing internal and external data to build visualizations.
- Performed root cause analysis and worked on inventory feed, stock out recovery and stock reporting for Home Depot.
- Worked with cross functional teams regarding product availability, allocation, cross shipping and transition planning.
- Generated reports like Sell-Out and KPI analysis for Executive management for Home Depot, Costco and BestBuy.
- Developed and maintained weekly SKU level demand signals like promotions, customer forecasts for new, active, discontinued products by utilizing statistical forecasting models to define best methods to forecast customer demand.

Supply Chain Analyst, Health Concepts LLC, New Jersey, USA

Jan 2018-Sep 2019

- Partnered with cross-functional teams to define and prioritize current and future requirements and opportunities for enhanced returns from the Wholesale Operations solution.
- Lead a team and influenced on demand planning strategies in order to maximize customer fill rates and minimized inventory redistribution by 6%.
- Managed KPI to measure, control and benchmark procurement processes including creation of recurring metrics reports to drive improvements by 10%.
- Implemented KPIs like Order measurement, Fill rate, Customer order cycle time, Supply chain cycle time, inventory turnover and design new processes to collect required data and work with teams to improve the metrics.
- Supported suppliers with demand forecasting and planning, resulting in reduction of costs by 12%.

Supply Chain Planner, Mahantesh United Pvt. Ltd

Jun 2014 - Jul 2015

- Managed KPI to measure, control and benchmark procurement processes including creation of recurring metrics reports to drive improvements by 10%.
- Developed and coordinated the tactical transportation plans for multiple client and/or manufacturing facilities or warehouses.
- Supported in defining on appropriate process improvement and problem-solving tools and methodologies such at Value Stream Mapping, Standard Work, 5S, Kaizen Events.
- Collaborated with several departments to fabricate and develop the Bill of materials.
- Conducted training sessions for implementation of WMS and conducted 5S audit throughout the Distribution Center (DC).
- Planned, scheduled and managed the inventory of raw materials and logistics.
- Recognized and resolved time and quality issues through corrective action plans, statistical process control, and time studies.

EDUCATION:

M.S in Project Management, Harrisburg University of Science and Technology, USA.

October 2022

• M.S. in Industrial Engineering, New Jersey Institute of Technology, USA.

May 2017

Relevant Coursework: Supply Chain Management, Cost Analysis, Advanced Statistics, Advanced Operations Research, Logistics, Design Manufacturability, Design for Manufacturability, System Simulation, Project Management.

• B.E. in Mechanical Engineering, SJCE, India

May 2014

CERTIFICATIONS and SKILLS:

- LEAN SIX SIGMA GREEN BELT CERTIFICATION
- SAP, Tableau, Power BI, MS Office, MS Outlook, Minitab, MATLAB, SolidEdge, CAD, CAM, Ansys, Visio, 8D, 5S, 5Y, Kaizen, SkuVault,